开萝尔:轮到你倒垃圾了……嗨!爸爸跟病人在一起的时候,
Carol: It's your turn to take out the garba...hey!
你不能去偷听,你知道的!
You know you can't listen in when Dad talks with one of his mental patients.
本:他没跟精神病人在一块儿,跟他在一块儿的是妈妈.
Ben: He's not talking to a mental patient!It's Mom.
开萝尔:那更糟.那你还是不应该去偷听.
Carol: Well that's probably worse.You still shouldn't snoop.
本:会很有意思的.
Ben: It's juicy stuff.
开萝尔:本,你不能……
Carol: Ben you can't..
本:他们在谈迈克.
Ben: It's about Mike.
迈克:嗨!本是不是又惹麻烦了,呃?
Mike: Hey!I see Ben's been into the goofy glue again, huh?
本:嘘.迈克,我们必须得警告你,否则就太迟了.
Ben: Ssshh.Mike we've got to warn you before it's too late.
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
开萝尔:掏五块钱.
Carol: For five Bucks.
本:对.
Ben: Yeah.
迈克:什么?你们以为,我和你们有血缘关系,我就会很弱智么?
Mike: What?You guys think I'm stupid just because I'm related to you?
开萝尔:好吧.那是你的死期.
Carol: Ok.Well it's your funeral.
迈克:得,得,我先欠你五块钱,好了吧.到底是什么?
Mike: Alright, alright, alright I owe you five Bucks.What is it?
本:今天你的成绩单寄到家了.
Ben: Your report card came in the mail today.
迈克:哦,不!
Mike: Oh no!
本:爸爸这么说的.
Ben: That's what Dad said.
迈克:会有多差?
Mike: How bad can it be?
本:爸爸说,你差不多已经马尾巴串豆腐,提不起来了.
Ben: Dad says you're this close to becoming a "good-for-nothing bum!"
迈克:好了,呣……就说你们没看到我.好么?
Mike: Ok, well...errm just tell 'em you haven't seen, ok?
开萝尔:等等.还有点小事儿,那五块钱呢?
Carol: Oh, wait a minute.There's the little matter of the five Bucks.
本:对.
Ben: Yeah.
迈克:能要的来你们就来要.
Mike: Try and collect.
本和开萝尔:嗨,迈克!!!!回家有你好瞧的,迈克!!!!
Ben and Carol: Hi Mike!!!!!It's good to see you home Mike!!!!
杰森:你哪儿都不准去.
Jason: Don't you go anywhere.
你妈妈我俩有话跟你说!
Your mom and I will wanna have a word with you in a few minutes!
迈克:把自己的亲生兄弟给出卖了,就为了五块钱,
Mike: Ok.Now was it really really worth it,
你觉得值么?
to sell your own brother out for a mere five Dollars?
本和开萝尔:哦,值啊!
Ben and Carol: Oh yeah!Sure...definitely!
麦琪:杰森,对迈克我们怎么办?
Maggie: Jason.What are we going to do with Mike?
杰森:麦琪,自从他幼儿园开始,
Jason: Well Maggie, we've been asking each other the same question ever
我们一直问的都是同一个问题.
since his first report card in kindergarten.
麦琪:可是,他再有一年半就毕业了.
Maggie: I know, but he's only a year and a half away from graduating.
杰森:D,D+,D-.
Jason: I wouldn't bet on it.D, D plus, D minus minus.
老师的评价,"我已经领教了,我准备不教了."
Teacher comment number sixty four, which is, "I've had it, I'm quitting teaching".
麦琪:哦!
Maggie: Oh!
杰森:因为我们一贯都希望老师们的真实评价……
Jason: Course the real comment is our old favourite here...
杰森和麦琪:"该生的潜力没有充分发挥".
Jason and Maggie: "The student is not realizing full potential".
麦琪:杰森,迈克毕业会成为什么样的人?
Maggie: Jason, what is going to become of Mike after he graduates?
上不了大学,
I mean, no college, no skills.
没有一技之长,
I mean what kind of a job can a person get when all they have is
就迷人的微笑其它什么都没有,这样的人能找到什么样的工作?
a charming smile and nothing to back it up?
杰森:他能去好莱坞,当演员.
Jason: He can go to Hollywood, become an actor.
麦琪:杰森,我知道,
Maggie: Jason, I realize that as a psychiatrist you work hard at not letting
作为一名精神病科大夫,你极力地不让自己的情绪左右自己.但是,
your emotions get the best of you.
我会问自己,"干么我不跟一个脾气火爆点儿的……泌尿科大夫结婚呢?"
But at this point I'm asking myself, "why didn't I marry a fiery...urologist?"
杰森:麦琪,我愿意思考,就不暴跳如雷.好了吧?
Jason: Maggie, I'd rather think than rant, ok?
麦琪:那,你现在正在思考什么呢?
Maggie: So, what are you thinking?
杰森:我在想,
Jason: Well, I think there must be a more effective way to get through
一定会有更有效的方法触动迈克.
to Mike.
麦琪:很好.是什么?
Maggie: Good.What is it?
杰森:我还不知道.
Jason: I don't know.
麦琪:这也叫思考?
Maggie: And you call that thinking?
杰森:得了.那你又怎么触动迈克?
Jason: Alright.How would you get through to him?
麦琪:我?
Maggie: Me?
杰森:对啊.
Jason: Yeah.
麦琪:我会……对,这是个好办法!
Maggie: Well...I'd...ok...I'd erm...ah yeah and this is good!
你明天在波士顿大学做的那个演讲,
You know that speech you're giving at Boston College tomorrow?
还记得么?就是你让我听了三遍的那篇.
one you made me listen to three times.
杰森:哦,我记起来了,是你要求听三遍的那篇.
Jason: No, I know the one you asked to hear three times.
麦琪:就那篇.把迈克也给带上,
Maggie: That's the one.Anyway take him with you.Show him round the campus.
让他看一看大学校园,让他看一看他可能会失去的是什么.
Let him see what he'll be missing, if he doesn't get his act together.
杰森:麦琪,这主意太绝了.
Jason: Maggie, that's a terrible idea.
麦琪:是么?
Maggie: It is?
杰森:知不知道我会怎么办?我会带他给我一起去波士顿,
Jason: Do you know what I could do?
然后侧面地跟他讲讲大学.
I could take him with me to Boston and soft sell him about college.
麦琪:啊!带他去看校园?
Maggie: Ah!Show him around the campus?
杰森:对!
Jason: Yes!
麦琪:让他明白他将失去的是什么.
Maggie: Let him see what he'll be missing.
杰森:对.
Jason: Yes.
麦琪:为什么,我想知道你从哪儿得到的这些主意?
Maggie: Why I wonder where you come up with this stuff.
杰森:麦琪,非常好.哦,
Jason: Maggie, this is great.Oh, Michael!!
迈克!!!他将无法抵挡我魔法师般的说服,我要整个击末都和他呆在一起.
He won't be able to resist my magical powers of persuasion.
嗨,迈克,请坐.
I'll have the whole weekend to spend with him.Hi Mike.Have a seat.
迈克:啊,别说了.
Mike: Ah hold it!Alright alright.
我知道你想说什么,我知道你们一直在讨论我的未来,
I know what this is all about,
而我本人,有一些话要说.请坐,
I know you guys have been talking about my future plans,
爸爸.现在,
and I myself have a few remarks on this subject.Have a seat, Dad.
告诉我,你们大惊小怪这是在干什么?
Now, what's all this fuss about the future?
麦琪:迈克!
Maggie: Mike!!
迈克:不,妈妈!!现在,我已经决定了,我一定要非常成功,挣很多很多的钱.
Mike: Naa Mom!!Now I have got this handled, alright?Now I have made a
decision in my life to become very successful and make a lot of money
杰森:啊?!
Jason: Aha?!
迈克:你们俩现在可能在问自己,"怎么去实现这个目标呢"?
Mike: Now you guys are probably asking yourselves, "how is he going to do this?"
杰森和麦琪:怎么去实现这个目标呢?
Jason and Maggie: How is he going to do this?
迈克:都写在这儿了,白纸黑字.
Mike: It's all right here in black and white Mom.
麦琪:"维纳*福伯的平庸之辈挣大钱的方法"?
Maggie: "Vinnie Furbo's shiftless man's way to big bucks"?
迈克:继续读.
Mike: Keep reading.
麦琪:"我挣了一百万块,可我和你一样只是个普通人.
Maggie: "I made a million smakaroos and I'm just an average Joe like you.
不需要高深的大学教育,
And you don't need a big deal college education, or any special skills.
也不需要什么特殊的技能,所有需要的只是每周可自由支配的两个小时和一脸迷人的微笑"???
All you need is two free hours a week and a winning smile"??
迈克:这是对我的召唤,现在我不想占用你们更多的时间,但是我向你们保证----如果我挣到我的第一个一百万,我会给你们买几套像样的衣服.
Mike: I've found my calling.Ok, now I won't take any more of you guys' time but I willpromise you this- when I make my first million, I will buy you guys some decent clothes.
杰森:迈克,我能看一眼么?
Jason: Mike, could I see that please?
迈克:可以,爸爸.
Mike: Yeah, sure Dad.
杰森:儿子,再重复一遍,你能不能找把椅子给我坐下?
Jason: Ah son, as I said before, will you have a seat please?
迈克:啊---爸爸,又要给我上课是么?大学教育的重要性?
Mike: Ahhhh Dad, is this gonna be another one of those college talks?
杰森:不.
Jason: No.
麦琪:对,是的.
Maggie: Ah yes it is.
杰森:不,不是的.
Jason: No it isn't.
麦琪:对,是的.
Maggie: Yes it is.
杰森:不,不是的.
Jason: No, it isn't.
麦琪:是.
Maggie: Is.
迈克:有什么目的?
Mike: What's the catch?
杰森:没什么目的,迈克.
Jason: There's no catch Mike.Come on, it will be fun.
不要多想,会很有意思的.
Just the two of us hanging out in bean town.
只有我们二人,四处畅游于大学校园中.最近,
You've been under a lot of academic pressure lately,
你的学习压力也比较大,也许你真正的需要就是一个短暂的休息.
and well maybe what you really need is just a break.
来了,这是你应该得到的!!
Come on, you've earned it!!
本:所有这些垃圾最后是怎么处理的?
Ben: Where does all this stupid garbage end up?
开萝尔:垃圾会被送到工厂,变成录相带,然后,录制成摇滚音像.
Carol: Well, it's taken to a factory, turned into video tape and then they record rock videos onto it.
本:哇.
Ben: Wow.
迈克:开萝尔,我想借你的行李箱用一下?
Mike: Carol, I need you to lend me a suitcase.
开萝尔:是不是爸爸妈妈决定把你赶出家门了?肯定是!!!
Carol: They decided to kick you out of the house?Yes!!
迈克:不是的,没有赶我出门.
Mike: No.They didn't kick me out of the house.
开萝尔:女孩会经常做梦的.
Carol: A girl can dream.
迈克:实事上,爸爸准备带我去波士顿,
Mike: As a matter of fact, Dad's taking me on a trip to Boston,
给男孩的小小的休息.
for a little guy getaway.
开萝尔:等等,
Carol: Wait a minute.
你被叫进去是因为你的糟糕的成绩,其结果是一次去波士顿的旅行.
You get called in 'cause of your crummy grades,
那我到底哪里做错了?
and end up on a trip to Boston?What am I doing wrong here?
迈克:太多了,开萝尔.不过,
Mike: A lot Carol.But that's not the point.
问题的关键还不在于在.实话告诉你吧,爸爸和妈妈根本就没打算给我谈成绩的事儿.
And for your information, Mom and Dad didn't even wanna talk about my grades.
开萝尔:什么?
Carol: What?
迈克:没,没什么,他们甚至于也没有发什么脾气.他们情绪非常之好.
Mike: Na, no, they didn't even bring 'em up.They were in a great mood.
开萝尔:迈克!如果爸爸和妈妈在看了你的成绩之后情绪非常之好,
Carol: Mike!If Mom and Dad were in a great mood after seeing your grades,
那只能是做梦.
then we've just experienced a miracle.
我感觉,这整座房子就要成为一个神龛了,
I mean, my guess is, that this house is going to turn into a shrine.
And then thousands of D students are gonna line up
迈克*希佛,劣等生的守护神.
to light candles in your name!!Mike Seaver, patron Saint of underachievers.
迈克:行李箱,我不借了.
Mike: I'll get my own suitcase.
本:哦!这批垃圾肯定写满了"摇滚".
Ben: Oh!This patch of garbage has definitely "rock" written all over it.
开萝尔:本,如果我告诉你说,
Carol: Ben, if I told you that Mom and Dad didn't yell at Mike because
因为成绩爸爸和妈妈刚才没有对迈克发脾气,相反,
of grades.And instead, Dad was taking Mike on a fun trip to Boston.
爸爸还要带迈克去波士顿,那你会怎么想?
What would you think?
本:我会认为,爸爸想诱使迈克让他燃起上大学的热情,方法就是带他去自己的母校.
Ben: I'd think that Dad was trying to trick Mike into caring about college, by taking him to his old school.
开萝尔:本,你说得对!这完全是设计好的!!
Carol: Ben, you're right!This is all a trick!!
本:没错.你会怎么想?
Ben: Sure.What'd you think?
空乘:机长已经取消了系紧安全带的信号,请随意自由活动.
Air hostess: The Captain has extinguished the fastened seat belt sign, please feel free to move aimlessly around the cabin.
杰森:迈克,我们的旅行已经开始了.
Jason: Alright Mike, we're on our way.
迈克:对.
Mike: Yeah.
杰森:嗨,留意到了么,你我共同出行,这是第一次?
Jason: Hey, you realize this is the first time you and I have taken a trip alone together?
迈克:是的.
Mike: Yeah.
杰森:只有两个男人外出旅行.
Jason: I mean as just two men hanging out.
迈克:嗨,爸爸.你说什么呢?要不要我们找几个女人,呃?
Mike: Hey Dad, what do you say we look for some chicks, huh?
杰森:真搞笑.不管怎么说,这周末我们会好好开心一下.
Jason: Very funny.Hey we're gonna have some big fun this weekend though.
迈克:对.
Mike: Yeah.
杰森:我唯一的任务是在学校里做篇演讲,
Jason: The only obligation I have is to make that speech on campus,
而且时间不会很长.嗨,
and that's not going to take very long.
反正我得去学校,
Hey, as long as I have to go to the campus anyway,
跟我一块儿去吧?我可以给你介绍一下我的大学,
why don't you come with me?I could show you around my college.
我生命一些最好的时光是在这里渡过的.
The place where I had some of the best years of my life.
迈克:不,我不知道,
Mike: Na..I don't know Dad.
迈克.也许我只想待在饭店里,然后找几个女人.
I think maybe I wanna stay at the hotel and find some women.
杰森:迈克,如果你感兴趣的只是女人,那你会错过一个大好机会.
Jason: Mike.Well, if it's women you're interested in, you know, you're missing a bet notcoming to this campus.
迈克:是么?
Mike: Yeah?
杰森:哦,当然!好几百,而且所有的人都对知识如饥似渴.
Jason: Oh yeah!Hundreds.And all of them hungry for..knowledge.
迈克:我觉得,错过这次演讲可能真的会是个遗憾,是不是爸爸?
Mike: So, I guess it would be a shame to miss that speech, wouldn't it Dad?
杰森:对.你可以一整天都待在那儿,你是……
Jason: Right.Hey you know we could spend the whole day there.Are you...
空乘:来点坚果么?(注:nuts,谐音,双关.坚果,又指傻子等.)
Hostess: Nuts??
杰森:来点,我太喜欢了.
Jason: Yeah, I love these.
迈克:我也来点,非常感谢.
Mike: Yeah.Thanks.
空乘:你们哪位想要点饮料?
Hostess: Do either of you like something to drink?
杰森:哦……我想要……
Jason: Oh...I'd...
空乘:因为航班太短,
Hostess: Because no one else does on kind of such a short flight and
其它人都没有要饮料.如果我不需要把饮料车推出来的话,
everything.And it would really save me a lot of trouble if I didn't have
会真的省去很多麻烦.
to haul out that drink cart.
杰森:不要了,没关系的,谢谢你.
Jason: No, it's fine thank you.
知道么,我记得自己第一次去这所大学的时候,
Well, you know, I remember when I first went to that college.
我什么也不知道,不知道自己以后要干什么.但是,
I had no clue what I wanted to do with the rest of my life.
有一种东西,一种有所作为的进取心会把这些问题的答案全部带入你的视野之中,
But there's something about being there that brought it all into focus,
你能明白么?当你有所领悟的时候,展现在你面前的就只有一种职业选择.
you know?And that's when I realized, there was only one career for me.
迈克:呃.
Mike: Huh.
杰森:赛车手.而他们把我送进了精神病医学校,之后,所有的就只是精神健康学史.
Jason: Race car driver.So they sent me to the school psychiatrist, and the rest is all mental health history.
男人:嗨,孩子!我能不能借你的呕吐袋用一下?
Man: Hey kid!Can I borrow your barf bag?
迈克:可以,您留着吧.
Mike: Yeah.Keep it.
男人:还有您的?
Man: Yours too.
杰森:哦?没问题,慢用.
Jason: Oh?Sure, enjoy.
男人:谢谢.
Man: Thanks.
杰森:好了,迈克,你的人生规划是什么呢?
Jason: So Mike.What are your plans?
迈克:啊----,我没那么多要求,什么都行,爸爸.对我来说,这次旅行只是一个男人的周末.
Mike: Ahhh, I'm wide open Dad.This is just gonna be a guys' get-away weekend for me.
杰森:我不是指这周末的计划,我是指你未来的计划.
Jason: You know, I don't just mean for the weekend, I mean for the future too.
比如,从现在开始十年,你对自己的设计是什么?
Like err, how do you see yourself ten years from now?
迈克:十年……太长了.
Mike: Ten years......old.
迈克:迈克,那时你就26了.
Jason: Mike, you'll be twenty six.
迈克:对.
Mike: Yeah.
杰森:好了,从现在开始两年,你对自己的设计.
Jason: Alright.Two years from now.
迈克:两年,呃……
Mike: Two years err...
杰森:最好还是换一个吧,这样,
Jason: Better yet, tell me how you see yourself two days after graduation.
告诉我你毕业之后两天你对自己的设计.你打算要做什么?
What are you gonna be doing?
迈克:哦,这个简单.我,埃德,还有鲍纳,我们会去Lauderdale城堡.
Mike: Oh simple.Me and Eddy and Boner, we're heading down to Fort Lauderdale.
杰森:好的.毕业之后,一周呢.
Jason: Alright.One week after graduation.
迈克:还是结伴游玩.
Mike: Still partying.
杰森:迈克,得了!在你还没明白是怎么回事呢,毕业已经如期而至了.
Jason: Mike, come on!Before you know, it's going to be graduation.
迈克:好了,爸爸,还有一年半呢.
Mike: Come on Dad, it's a whole year and a half away.
杰森:可是,有些东西就在你身边,
Jason: Yeah but you get the things that you get a chance to do now.
你现在有机会去挣取.你现在即将做出的决定,
And the decisions you're gonna make,
将会影响你以后的生活.时间宝贵啊.
they're gonna affect you the rest of your life.Time is precious.
迈克:哦哇爸爸!看到那个美女了么,去那边大厅了.我得去问个究竟.
Mike: Oh wow Dad!See that fox heading over to the lounge?I gotta go check her out.
杰森:迈克,我在跟你说话……时间宝贵啊.
Jason: Mike.We're talking...about time being precious.
迈克:跟我讲讲!飞机15分钟后降落.我得活动活动!
Mike: Tell me about it!This plane lands in fifteen minutes.I gotta move!
杰森:迈克!
Jason: Mike!
迈克:啊,她不感兴趣,爸爸.她结过婚了.
Mike: Ahh, she wasn't interested Dad.She was married.
杰森:迈克,我不想谈那个.
Jason: Mike, I don't wanna talk about that.
迈克:我也不想,不过,有点沉闷.
Mike: Me either, it's depressing.
杰森:我想继续刚才讨论的话题,可以么?
Jason: I want to stick to the original topic of discussion, ok?
迈克:刚才讨论的话题是什么,爸爸?
Mike: What was the original topic Dad?
杰森:你打算怎么提高你的成绩,迈克.
Jason: How you're gonna improve your grades, Mike.
迈克:是从什么时候开始这个成为我们之间的确话题的?
Mike: Since when did that become the topic?
杰森:很多年前.
Jason: Years ago.
迈克:好了,爸爸.我想像中的休息放松不是这样子.
Mike: Ah come on Dad.This isn't my idea of a guy's get-away.
杰森:我怎么才能跟你说明白?我怎么才能使你醒悟,你现在做的事情将会影响你整个的日后生活?
Jason: How do I get through to you?I mean, how do I make you realize that for the rest of your life, you're going to be affected by what you do now?
迈克:爸爸,什么使你如此确定我不明白这道理呢?
Mike: Dad, what makes you so sure I don't?
杰森:上一次是什么时候,
Jason: When's the last time,
你做家庭作业超过十五分钟?
you spent more than fifteen minutes doing your homework?
迈克:爸爸,这不在于我花费的时间,
Mike: Dad, it's not the quantity of time that I spend; it's the quality,
而在于质量,对不对?
right?
杰森:你就是不明白,是不是?
Jason: You just don't get it do you?
如果我把你的车扣了,直到你的成绩进步再发还给你,这么做有用么?
I mean would it help if I took away your car until your grades came through?
空乘:请注意!请注意!我们现在有一个小小的紧急情况……
Hostess: Attention!Attention!Excuse me!We have a small emergency...
乘客:哦,不不不,想撞机了么!!!
Passenger: Oh no no no, we're gonna crash!!!
空乘:不!,不,应该不会.
Hostess: No!No, I don't think so.
乘客:认为? 哦!!!
Passenger: Think?Aarrggghhh!!!!!
空乘:嗨嗨,我们只是有一个医疗紧急情况.
Hostess: Hey hey, we just got a little medical emergency here.Lighten up!
请注意了,乘客当中有哪位是医生?
Now, is there a doctor on board?
杰森:我是.
Jason: I'm a doctor.
空乘:啊,太好了!坐在您身后的那位女士,这位是她的丈夫,她要临产了.
Hostess: Ah, terrif!Hi!The woman sitting behind you.This guy's wife, she says she's going into labour.
杰森:好的,我可以先看一下.
Jason: Well, I can take a look at her.
男人:嗨,大夫,您难道不需要妇科手术要用的药械箱,或者其它什么东西么?
Man: Hey Doc.Don't you need a little black bag, or something?
杰森:不,我是个精神病科大夫.
Jason: No.I'm a psychiatrist.
男人:哦,大夫.她不是在想她自己要生孩子了,她已经快要生了.
Man: Oh well Doc.She doesn't think she's having a baby, she's having a baby.
杰森:精神病科大夫也是医生.
Jason: A psychiatrist is a medical doctor.
男人:哦?嗨……千万别告诉我妻子你是精神科的,呃?
Man: Oh?Hey...er...don't tell my wife you're a head shrinker, huh?
杰森:你好,嗨,我是杰森*希佛,
Jason: Hello, hi, I'm Jason Seaver.I understand you're going into labour.
我听说你就要临盆了.好的,收缩的间隔时间有多长?
Ok, alright, how far apart are the contractions?
女人:我的羊水出来了!!
Woman: My water broke!!
杰森:你能先用机长的无线电对讲机先叫一辆救护车么?
Jason: Would you have the Captain radio ahead for an ambulance?
男人:救护车!救护车!
Man: Ambulance!Ambulance!
杰森:一切顺利,一切顺利.我们马上就会落地,还有好大一会儿宝贝才会降生呢.
Jason: Everything's fine, everything's fine.We'll be on the ground, long before the babyarrives.
男人:哦.好.
Man: Oh.Ok.
机长:嗨,大家好,
Captain: Hi folks.This is Captain Kirk.
本人是机长.预定机场有雾,所以……我们得盘旋一回儿,
Lowland International is having a little fog problem and...
所以请各位放松,喝点饮料.
we're gonna circle a bit, so relax and have a drink.
男人:哦,不不不不不!!!一切都乱了套了这儿.
Man: Oh no no no no no!!!Everything's going wrong here.
杰森:冷静点儿,卡特尔,没必要心慌失措,一切正常.
Jason: Calm down Carter, there's no reason to panic, everything's fine.
空乘:对,你看我一点都不惊慌,而且我还得把那个破车推出来送饮料.
Hostess: Yeah.You don't see me throwing a fit, and I've got to haul out that stupid drinks cart.
杰森:好了,这边地方大点儿,你可以稍微舒适一点儿.
Jason: Come on there's more room up here, you'll be more comfortable.
男人:为什么我们需要大点儿的地方?将要发生什么事?你说过,我们马上就要降落,难道没说过么?难道没说过么?
Man: Why do we need more room?What's going to happen?You said we'd be on the ground by now.Didn't he?Didn't he say that?Didn't he?
男人:好,现在我们做什么?水,撕床单,还是其它什么?
Man: Ok.What do we do now?Water, rip sheets, what?
女人:亲爱的,你吓着我了!
Woman: Honey, you're scaring me!
杰森:你也吓着我了.你不能坐在那边么?
Jason: You're scaring me too, damn it.Will you sit over there please.
苏珊,你就坐在这儿.
Susan, you sit right there.
女人:坐在魔法地毯里?
Woman: In the magic carpet lounge?
Jason: Yeah.Dan, you know you could be a big help if you'd just take
a
知道么?不要慌,镇静.
stroll, alright?Just calm down.
男人:我要去外面小走一会儿,会让我感觉舒服点儿的.
Man: That's it.I'll take a nice brisk walk outside.It'll do me good.
杰森:迈克,你能不能照看照看他?
Jason: Mike, will you watch him please?
迈克:好的,爸爸.不过,如果他要开舱门,我就不跟着他了.
Mike: Alright Dad, but if he opens the door, he's on his own.
女人:(叫)
Woman: Oooohhh ooohhh oooohhh!!!
杰森:舒服点了么,苏珊?
Jason: Yes.Are you comfortable Susan?
女人:五个月以来,我都没舒服过,大夫!
Woman: I haven't been comfortable in five months Doctor!
空乘:大夫,有句话儿,可以单独跟您谈么?
Hostess: Doctor.A word in our private team.
杰森:可以.
Jason: Yeah.
女人:不.
Woman: No.
杰森:机长刚才说了什么?
Jason: What did the captain say?
空乘:他说了还有一个小时雾才能散,
Hostess: He said it would take an hour for the fog to clear,
而去附近机场则至少需要四十五分钟.
and at least forty five minutes to divert to another airport.
杰森:该死!孩子还有半小时就要生了.你去告诉机长,要么他把飞机落下去,要么把我变成个妇科大夫.
Jason: Damn!This baby's coming in an half an hour.You tell your Captain Kirk
he's either got to land this plane, or beam me up an obstetrician
空乘:哦,真可爱.
Hostess: Oh.That's so cute.
女人:啊---------!!!
Woman: Aaarrggghh!!!
男人:我告诉过她,我们不应该坐飞机.
Man: I told her we shouldn't fly.The doctor said no.
医生说过不行.可是,她听劝了么?
But did she listen to me?
迈克:显然没有.
Mike: Apparently not.
男人:她不会有事吧,你觉得呢?
Man: You think she'll be ok?
迈克:哦,她会没事的.我爸爸是个非常出色的精神病科大夫.
Mike: Oh yeah, she'll be fine.Yeah my dad is a great psychiatrist.
男人:但是现在他要做的是另外一件事情.你的名字?
Man: But now he's dealing with the other end.What's your name?
迈克:啊……迈克.
Mike: Ah...Mike.
Man: What's my name?Dan!!!That's it!Ok, ok Mike.I'm feeling much better now
迈克,我现在感觉好多了,完全冷静下来了.
I'm feeling completely calm.
乘客:冷静??!!你为什么需要冷静?发生了什么事?
Passenger: Calm??!!Why shouldn't you be calm?What's going on?
杰森:继续用力,苏珊,继续用力.
Jason: Keep pushing Susan, keep pushing.
女人:什么时候才会不疼?
Woman: When does the pain stop?
杰森:大概得18年.
Jason: In about eighteen years.
男人:要生了!要生了!
Man: It's happening!It's happening!
杰森:Dan,控制一下你自己.
Jason: Dan, get a hold of yourself.
男人:哪里?(注:双关)
Man: Where?
女人:哪儿都行!
Woman: Birdycup!
男人:亲爱的!
Man: Sweetheart!
女人:吃点什么.
Woman: Munchkin!
男人:孩子们才这样!!
Man: Baby doll!
女人:讨厌……你给我离开这儿!你让我感觉真烦.
Woman: Booboo man...Get the hell out of here!You're making me feel awful.
男人:可是我是你的助手.
Man: Yeah, but I'm your coach.
女人:如果我需要助手,我第一个叫你.现在,出去.
Woman: If I need a coach, you're the first one I'll call.Now get out!!
杰森:只是就事论事,不要往心里去,Dan!
Jason: Don't take it personally Dan!
男人:我知道,我知道,医生.我上过生理课的,迈克,我知道女人在临盆的最后阶段会是什么样.
Man: Yeah.I know, I know Doc.I know.I took Lamonts classes Mike, and
I know a woman tends to freak out when she reaches the final stage of
labour.The final stage of labour
杰森:迈克!
Jason: Mike!
迈克:明白了,爸爸,跟我讲讲你上过的那些赛车课.
Mike: I got it Dad, it's ok.Tell me about those race car classes you took.
女人:啊----!
Woman: Aaarrrgghhhh!
空乘:有时间么?医生,
Hostess: Got a sec?Doctor, I have two messages from captain Kirk.
机长让我跟您两个口信.首先,
First he said he could have you on the ground in sixty five seconds but
他可以在65秒种之内降落,
he doesn't think you'd enjoy the landing.
但是你可能会受惊吓的;其次,我和我一样不介意你开的关于他的玩笑.
And second, he didn't care for your Captain Kirk joke as much as I did.
女人:啊----!
Woman: AAAaaaarrrrgghhh!!
男人:你听到了么?
Man: You hear that?
迈克:我觉得大家都听到了.哦,我无心的,真的是无心的.
Mike: I think everybody heard that.Oh I blew it.That's all there is too it.
别跟我争,我只是一个胆小鬼.继续,说出来吧.
Don't argue with me kid.I'm a wimp.Go ahead and say it.
迈克:好了.你确实是否个胆小鬼.
Mike: Ok.You're a wimp.
男人:有谁问你了么?你难道不会紧张激动么,
Man: Who asked you?
如果生孩子的是你的妻子?
Wouldn't you be freakin' out if your wife was having a baby?
迈克:有个老婆,我都会紧张激动的.
Mike: Heck, I'd freak out if I even had a wife.
男人:我是什么样的父亲?连自己的孩子出生都不能看,我的小孩会恨我的.啊,生孩子这个主意,真是个大错误.
Man: What kind of father am I?Can't even watch my own kid being born.I mean my kid's gonna...hate me.Ah, this whole deal of having a baby, big mistake.
迈克:嗨,我一直都没弄明白为什么人们还会生孩子.
Mike: Hey, I have never gotten why people even have kids.
男人:嗨!没人不知道自己为什么会要孩子.你生孩子,
Man: Hey!Everybody knows why you have kids.
你把新生命带到这个世界上来,这个人会成为你的一部分,会成为你生命的一部分.
You do it to bring somebody into the world who's part you and part your wife.
迈克:啊.
Mike: Aha.
男人:就像是有了个什么人在你的周围,他可以从你的错误当中汲取教训.就好像是,比方说,随着这条时空线索的延伸,在某处,突然地,我的孩子想说,"搬到皮兹堡",而我说,"不行,我之前已经在那儿住过了".如果他想更酷一点,想抽烟,那我就会告诉他,"不能抽,我戒了三年才成功.如果你曾想过辍学……那绝对不可以.因为,我辍学了,现在我悔恨终生!
Man: Yeah, I mean it's like having someone round who can learn from your mistakes.I mean like err say somewhere down the line all of a sudden my kid wants to say err, "move to Pittsburgh!" I say, "no way, I lived there".And if he ever wants to be cool and smoke, well, I'll tell him, "you aint gonna do that pal!It took me three years to quit.And if you ever, ever, think of quitting school...it'll be over my dead body.You see I done that and it stinks!"
迈克:好了,我不会辍学的,我不会的.
Mike: Alright, I won't quit.I won't.
男人:哦,对不起,迈克.我今天可能有些一反常态,呃?
Man: Oh.Sorry Mike.Guess I'm not myself today, huh?
迈克:嗨,没关系的,我认识的还有位父亲,他也是有点嚷嚷.
Mike: Hey, it's ok, I know another father who yells a little.
男人:如果这孩子要犯什么愚蠢的错误,我要怎么做呢?
Man: Yeah.What am I gonna do with this kid when he wants to make some stupid mistake?
迈克:"你要做什么",您这是什么意思?你打算把他纠正过来?
Mike: What do you mean, "what are you going to do"?You're gonna straighten him out.
男人:不,他会认为我干涉他个人的生活.
Man: Na, he'll just think I'm on his case.
迈克:他怎么想,有谁会在意?他只是一个孩子而已.现在,
Mike: So, who cares what he thinks, he's just a kid.Now who knows more?
谁知道的更多?你,还是你的孩子?
You or him?
男人:你说得对.
Man: You're right.
迈克:对,我说的确实对.
Mike: Yeah.I am.
男人:也许你应该生一个孩子,一个孩子.
Man: Maybe you ought to have a kid, kid.
男人:你听到了么?现在,是谁把这个孩子带到世界上的?
Man: Will you listen to that.Now who would bring a little baby on a plane?
这是我的孩子!我们的孩子!我们有孩子了!
The baby!It's a baby!It's my baby!It's our baby!We got a baby!
男人:亲爱的.
Man: Honey.
女人:亲爱的,我们有了一个儿子.
Woman: Honey.Honey, we have a son.
男人:儿子,嗨,迈克,是个男孩.
Man: A son.Hey Mike, it's a son.
迈克:好了,还有路要走呢!
Mike: Yeah right!Way to go!
男人:他还这么……这么的小.
Man: He's so...so young.
女人:他好漂亮哦.
Woman: Yeah!Isn't he beautiful?
杰森:恭喜你做了父亲.
Jason: Congratulations Pop.
男人:耶.
Man: Yeah.
杰森:谢谢你谢谢你谢谢你.
Jason: Thank you thank you thank you.
迈克:好了,爸爸!我得把这话再递给您,爸爸.你真的知道人你自己在干什么.
Mike: Alright Dad!I gotta hand it to you Dad.You really know what you're doing.
杰森:其中的有一部分功劳还得给你妈妈.
Jason: Well, I think we have to give some of the credit to the mother...
迈克:你真的是有两下子,爸爸.
Mike: You know you are really something.
杰森:谢谢.
Jason: Thank you.
迈克:爸爸,
Mike: Dad, this college thing.
关于大学这件事,如果您认为确实非常重要的话,
Erm, you know, if you think this is really important,
或许我应该最起码地去试它一试.
then maybe I should at least give it a shot.
杰森:什么意思,迈克?
Jason: What's the catch Mike?
迈克:没没,迈克,没有意思.刚才我一直在想.
Mike: No no Dad, there's no catch.I've just been thinking.
谁知道的更多呢?您,还是我?
I mean, who knows more?You or me?
男人:嗨,大夫,
Man: Hey Doc., from now on we're gonna have all our kids delivered by
从现在开始,我们准备让自己的孩子都由精神病科大夫来接生.
a psychiatrist.
女人:他是个精神病科大夫?
Woman: He's a psychiatrist?
电视:在今晚的常规新闻报道中,出现了喜剧的一幕!今天下午,一架驶往波士顿的航班起飞时一切正常……
TV: And in tonight's normal roundup, drama!This afternoon, what began as a routinecommuter flight to Boston...
开萝尔:波士顿!本,本,把电视调回来!
Carol: Boston!Ben, Ben, turn it back!
麦琪:波士顿!?
Maggie: Boston!?
电视:本和苏珊离开纽约的时候还是一对夫妇,而降落在波士顿的时候已经拥有了自己的家庭.
TV: Ben and Susan Columbo left New York as a couple that landed in Boston
一点儿没错,你一定猜到了.
as a family.That's right, you guessed it.Mrs.
苏珊生了一个七磅十二盎司重男婴,调皮可爱.
Columbo gave birth to a seven pound, twelve ounce, bouncing baby boy.
麦琪:看!你们的父亲.
Maggie: Look!It's your dad!
开萝尔:哦,还有迈克.
Carol: Oh and Mike.
电视:这名男婴是杰森*希佛医生接生的,而他是一名彻头彻尾的精神病科大夫.
TV: The newest Columbo was delivered by Doctor Jason Seaver,
本台记者问道,在三万英尺的高空接生有何感受."
who is of all things, apsychiatrist.
接生婆们做这个做这个已经不是一天两天了.哈哈"."
We asked him what it was like to deliver a baby at thirty thousand feet."
嗨,妈妈!"
Well Storks have been doing it for years.Ha ha"."Hi Mom!"
开萝尔,本和麦琪:嗨,迈克!!
Carol, Ben and Maggie: Hi Mike!!
电视:(杰森 讲话),嗨,如果你觉得这是新闻,等我回家,那才是真正的新闻.
TV: (Jason speaking) Hey if you think this is news, wait 'till I get home.
麦琪:起作用了.迈克准备上大学了!!
Maggie: It worked.Mike's going to college!!
开萝尔:哦,太好了,我们也要上电视了.
Carol: Oh great, it's to be on TV too.
电视:母子平安,一切正常.
TV: Mother and baby are doing fine.
麦琪:好么?
Maggie: Well?
杰森:我不跟你吵,麦琪,我看起来没什么不好的.
Jason: Well, I can't argue with you Maggie, I looked good!
麦琪:要不要我再重新放一遍?
Maggie: Well should I rewind it?
本:不不,一个下午放三遍就足够了.
Jason: No, no, I think three times is enough for one afternoon.
麦琪:亲爱的,当我在电视上看到你的表现是那么的精彩的时候,你知道在我心头闪现的是什么么?
Maggie: Well honey, when I see how good you look on TV.You know what occurs to me?
杰森:什么?
Jason: What?
麦琪:可能你已经错过了你的职业发展方向.我觉得你在电视上表现也很棒.
Maggie: Maybe you've missed your calling.
你有没有这么想过?
You know I think you'd be great on Television.Did it ever occur to you?
杰森:麦琪,做我现在做的事,我非常高兴.
Jason: Maggie.I'm perfectly happy doing what I'm doing.
麦琪:只是想想而已.
杰森:呣.我是杰森!!不.
00:22:43,700
Maggie: Well.Just a thought. Jason: Umm.Here's Jason!!Na.